（葉風・心の声）≪信じられん…。→
I can't believe it...
The whole situation has turned on its head,
彼氏というひと言だけで→
状況が　ひっくり返るとは…≫
just with the word "boyfriend."
≪それらすべてを
天秤にかけてすら→
All of that has been put on a scale, and all has been outweighed
釣り合わぬまでに
愛花という少女は…≫
by this girl named Aika.
（滝川吉野）じゃあ→
All right.
立証を始めるぞ。
Here's my theory.
Episode 10
How to Make
a Time Machine
この世と　この世の理を造った
はじまりの樹。
The Tree of Genesis, which made this world and its logic,
葉風さんは
その加護を最大限に受けている。
completely protects Ms. Hakaze.
真広　そんな葉風さんに→
Mahiro, taking into account her privileged position,
完全に勝ち目がなくなる
なんてことがあると思うか？
do you really think she has no chance of winning?
Isn't it because the Tree of Genesis hasn't fully awakened?
（不破真広）はじまりの樹は
完全に目覚めていないから→
That's why she's vulnerable, right?
そんな隙もある
って話じゃなかったか？
はじまりの樹を倒せる絶園の樹が
あんなにも　でかくなってるんだ。
The Tree of Exodus that can defeat the Tree of Genesis has grown so large.
I'm sure the world's logic has become a bit screwed up.
理とやらも
少しは　おかしくなるだろうよ。
そうだね。　だから　葉風さんは今→
True.
It is why Ms. Hakaze is currently at a disadvantage.
不利な状況に追い込まれている。
But that alone doesn't mean she's lost.
でも　不利ってだけで
負けが決まったわけじゃない。
考えてもみろ。
僕らは　なぜ　ここに来た。
Just think about it.
Why did we come here?
お前じゃなきゃ
ここまで来れなかった。
Had it been anyone but you, we'd never have gotten this far.
Had it been anyone but you, Ms. Hakaze wouldn't have gotten any help.
お前じゃなきゃ
葉風さんに手を貸しはしなかった。
Given all that, can you really dismiss
そんなお前が
葉風さんの人形を拾ったことを→
picking up Ms. Hakaze's doll as mere coincidence?
ただの偶然で片づけられるか？
そんな偶然があるものか！
Coincidences like that don't happen.
そこには　葉風さんを勝たせる
はじまりの樹の理があるはずだ！
This must be the will of the Tree of Genesis working in Ms. Hakaze's favor.
（左門）
≪この少年　よく言い切る…≫
This boy is a smooth talker.
それに　鎖部左門も変じゃないか？
Besides, don't you think there's something off about Kusaribe Samon?
He's been certain that we've been reaching Ms. Hakaze through time
僕らが　時間を越えて　葉風さんと
つながってるなんてむちゃを→
right from the start.
頭から確信してた。
（通信）いくら魔法使いでも
最初に考える可能性か？
Sure, he's a mage, but is a time shift really the most obvious conclusion?
（通信）まあ　時間のずれなんて
普通は考えねぇわな。
Well, I guess it's not the first explanation one might consider.
だから　鎖部左門は→
Then I can only assume
僕らみたいなのが
ここに来ることも→
that Kusaribe Samon knew from the very beginning
that someone like us would arrive, and that Ms. Hakaze would communicate with us through time.
葉風さんが
時間を越えてつながるのも→
最初から
想定していたとしか思えない。
And how did you come up with this crazy hypothesis?
なんで
そんなむちゃな想定をする？
Since he feared the consequence of something like this happening,
その事態をおそれ→
それに対応する手を
考えなければいけなかったからだ。
he had to prepare a countermeasure in advance.
へへっ。　ってことは→
In other words, as things stand,
his victory has yet to be confirmed.
今の状態じゃ
まだ　あいつの勝利は→
確定してないってことか。
そうだ。
That's right.
時間の檻に封じ込められている
という葉風さんを→
Meaning that there's still a way to bring Ms. Hakaze back,
ここに戻せる手があるってことだ。
（左門）くっ！
even if she's trapped in a prison of time.
鎖部左門は　それをないと思わせ→
Kusaribe Samon's trying to make it sound impossible.
Trying to fool us, Ms. Hakaze, and the world's logic,
僕らと葉風さん…
つまり　この世の理をもだまし→
all in order to win!
勝ちを得ようとしてるんだよ！
（夏村）
魔具を身につけているようだが→
It appears you wield a talisman.
However, your borrowed power will give you no advantage over me!
今の私に
そのような付け焼き刃は→
通用せん！
退くが得策と心得られよ。
It would be wise for you to retreat.
Magic has hurt me twice before.
（山本）
魔法には　過去に２回ばかり→
痛い目に遭わされてるの。
だから→
So,
I'm in need of some retribution to make amends!
ここらで　やり返しとかないと
気が収まらなくてね！
Tell me your name, mage.
名前を聞かせて　魔法使い。
（夏村）
覚えてもらうほどの名前は→
I do not have a name
important enough for you to remember.
持ち合わせていない！
はあ～～！
ガキン！
（早河）あのバカ…。
That fool.
（自衛官）航空総隊より入電。→
Telegram from the Air Force.
Fighter jets scrambled from Misawa and Tsuiki to provide close air support!
三沢および　築城のＦが
第１次近接航空支援のため出撃。→
富士到達まで　約３０分。
Thirty minutes until arrival at Mt. Fuji.
（早河）こうなったら　とことん
時間稼ぎしてもらうしかあるまい。
We just have to hope that she'll buy us enough time.
面白いな。
Interesting...
He can't really beat Hakaze, who's backed by the world's logic.
この世の理が味方する葉風には
勝てねぇ。
But if he succeeds in making Hakaze think that she's lost,
でも
葉風に　完全に負けたと思わせ→
and making cast aside her resolve to resist and persevere...
自分から勝つ可能性を
抵抗する意志を捨てさせれば→
What then, huh?
あるいは…　か？
時間の檻なんてものに
閉じ込められたら→
It'd be normal for someone trapped in a prison of time to lose all hope.
普通は絶望するからな。
鎖部左門の狙いは　それだ。
That's exactly what Kusaribe Samon wants.
（通信）
葉風さんが絶望している間に→
With Ms. Hakaze in despair,
he planned to revive the Tree of Exodus.
絶園の樹を復活させる。
その時間さえ稼げれば→
He didn't care if the truth came out later, as long as he could buy some time.
あとでバレても
かまわないってわけだ。
どうです？　左門さん。
How's that sound, Samon?
≪確かに　我らの狙いは　それだ≫
Indeed, that was precisely my gambit.
≪この世の理が味方する姫様には
勝てん≫
With the world's logic on her side, I cannot defeat the princess.
≪不利な状況を作り出すのが
精一杯だ≫
It took everything I had to put her at a disadvantage.
≪だが
どうにか　それには成功した≫
I managed to do so at long last.
After much thinking and plotting,
≪考えに考えて組み上げた→
I finally devised a plan to outwit the princess and the logic of the Tree of Genesis.
姫様と世の理をだます策が
見事に　はまっていたのだ≫
≪それを…→
And yet...
それを　こうも
たやすく見抜かれるとは…≫
This boy saw through it so easily.
≪これも　姫様に味方する
世の理ゆえか？≫
Is this also due to the world's logic siding with the princess?
≪だが　まだ完全に我らの策を→
However,
they have not seen through everything.
見抜かれたわけではない≫
なるほど　一応　筋は通っているな。
だが→
Very well.
You make valid points.
However,
（通信）
肝心の問題を解決していないぞ。
you have yet to resolve the most important matter here.
（葉風・通信）そうだ　吉野。→
He's right, Yoshino.
貴様の言うことは
そうとも考えられるというだけだ。
For the moment, your theory is, at most, a mere possibility.
It's true that the princess is trapped in a dimension two years in the past.
（左門）２年前の時空間に　姫様が
閉じ込められているのは事実だ。→
But how do you propose to retrieve her?
その姫様を
どうやって　ここに戻せる？→
Her body hangs right there.
死体も
そこに吊るされているのだぞ。
その絶対的な時間の檻を
お前は破れるというのか？
Do you claim that you can break through the ultimate prison of time?
破れはせん！
You cannot!
ならば
お前の仮説は　砂の城も同じ。
Therefore, your argument is invalid.
非現実的な言葉遊びにすぎん！
Your words are meaningless sophistry.
だな　吉野。
He's right, Yoshino.
I don't think it's possible to break through the time prison.
俺も　この時間の檻ってやつを
破れるとは思えねぇよ。
If we did, the past would change.
破れたら　過去を変えちまう。
A time paradox would occur.
タイムパラドックスが起きる。
ありえねぇ。
It's inconceivable.
それでも　破れる根拠か→
If you can't provide solid proof
that there's some way to break through,
具体的な方法が立証できなきゃ→
I can't go over to your side.
お前の側にはつけねぇぞ？
（左門）≪それでいい
それが当然の判断だ≫
That's exactly right.
That is exactly how you should think.
≪ただし　時間の檻を破る方法は→
Although, in reality, there is indeed a way to break through the prison.
存在するのだがな≫
The world's logic ensures the princess's victory.
≪姫様が勝つというのが
この世の理≫
≪それを　逆に利用するのだ≫
So we take advantage of that.
The Kusaribe clan spent three generations
≪鎖部一族が
三代にわたって試行を重ね→
painstakingly constructing this.
ようやく編み出した≫
≪姫様でさえ　そう簡単に
考えつくものではない≫
This isn't something that even the princess could easily figure out.
Let alone some boy who knows barely anything about magic.
≪ましてや　魔法について
ろくに知らぬ少年になど…≫
Actually, the time prison itself is an illusion.
いや　時間の檻自体　錯覚なんだよ。
タイムパラドックスもない。
（左門）あぁ…。
So there won't be any time paradox.
僕らは
２年間の時間のずれがあると→
We're being tricked into thinking that there is an actual two-year difference.
思い込まされてるだけなんだ。
≪この少年は　何を言っている!?≫
What is he saying?
葉風さん　あなたは
その島で４か月ほど過ごした。
Ms. Hakaze, you've spent about four months on that island.
You are certain of this, right?
それは間違いありませんね？
Yes.
日数は　きちんと数えていた。
I made sure to count the days carefully.
でも　葉風さん→
But, Ms. Hakaze,
did you also calculate how much time it took to transfer you to that island?
（通信）その島に
放り出されるまでの時間は→
計算に
入れてないんじゃありませんか？
Huh?
えっ？
（通信）あなたは→
You were put to sleep by Kusaribe Samon,
鎖部左門によって眠らされ→
stuffed into a barrel, and dumped on the island.
樽詰めにされて
そこに放り出された。
Isn't that what you think?
そう思ってますよね？
あぁ…。
でも→
But...
２年間　こちらで眠らされたあと→
What if you were first put to sleep for two years,
樽詰めにされて　そこに
放り出されていたらどうします？
then stuffed into a barrel and dumped on the island?
（通信）
眠らされていた葉風さんは→
Since you were asleep,
you wouldn't have realized that two years had passed.
自分の外で
２年が過ぎたことに気付きません。
時間の経過が分かる材料が
まるでない無人島で→
Trapped on a deserted island, with no concrete way to tell time,
この人形を通して
僕らとつながれば…。
and then finally able to communicate with us through this doll...
私は　２年後の未来世界と
つながっていると思い込む。
I would think that I was connected to a world two years in the future.
I guess if we spoke to someone who was unaware they'd slept for two years,
寝てる間に　２年過ぎたのを
知らないヤツと話したら→
it'd feel like a gap in time.
そりゃ２年ずれるか。
≪違うぞ
お前たちは間違っている！≫
No... You're wrong.
同じ時空間にいても→
Even if we're in the same time,
since some distance separates us, it can feel like communication across time.
遠距離だと　時を越えて
会話してるように思える。
This prison of time isn't physical.
この時間の檻は
物理的な檻じゃない。
It's a psychological illusion.
心理的な錯覚の檻なんだ！
あっ…。
でもよ　吉野→
But then, Yoshino,
just what are those bones?
その骨はなんだ？
あの潤一郎ってヤツは　それを→
Didn't Juunichiro confirm that they were Hakaze's?
葉風のものと確認したんだろ？
なっ!?
２年も
彼女の体を好きにできるんだ。
They had two years to do what they wanted with her body.
この骨だって
僕らをだます小道具なんだよ。
These bones are just another prop to fool us.
一人の人間を
２年も眠らせたのを→
It was probably tough to make someone sleep for two years without them realizing it.
気付かせないのは
大変だろうけど→
でも
ある程度　魔法を利用できるし→
But they do have access to magic, and they didn't waste any time.
手間を惜しまなければ…
そうしなければ→
If it was the only way to trick her, that's probably what they did.
葉風さんをだませないとなれば
やったはずだ。
ふっ。　こいつら
手間だけは惜しみそうにねぇよな。
They certainly don't seem like they'd waste time.
（通信）これで　僕らの勝利条件は→
Our victory once again lies with Ms. Hakaze's plan.
葉風さんの描いたものに戻った。
その葉風さんが　時間の檻に
閉じ込められていないなら…。
So if she isn't trapped in a time prison...
Mahiro!
真広！
この魔具を発動させれば→
If I activate this talisman,
左門の野郎は　葉風を
ここに戻さざるをえなくなる。
Samon will have no other choice but to bring Hakaze back here.
（左門）いや…。
ぐだぐだせずに→
No...
And then, Hakaze's victory will be decided instantly.
一発で
葉風の勝ちが決まるってわけか。
（左門）いや…。
最初から　俺らの計画どおり。
No...
So things will go exactly as we originally planned.
いや　待て　待て　待て！
No, wait, wait, wait...
待て～～!!
Wait!
We did not put the princess to sleep for two years!
我らは　２年も
姫様を眠らせるなどしておらん!!
その骨も
姫様のもので間違いない!!
And beyond doubt, those bones belong to the princess!
≪冗談ではないぞ！≫
This is not happening...
I shall not allow them to activate the talisman over a nonsensical theory!
≪そんな　でたらめな理屈で
魔具を発動させられるなど…≫
≪これは冤罪だ≫
This is a false accusation.
≪偽証による冤罪だ！≫
A false accusation based upon lies!
Do you have any proof?
証拠がありますか？
なっ!?
If we can't rely on Ms. Hakaze's sense of time,
葉風さんの時間感覚が
信用できないとなれば→
there's absolutely no proof of any time shift.
時間がずれている証拠なんて
ありませんよ。
Even with magic,
だいたい　いくら魔法でも→
時間を越えて会話できるなんて
非常識です。
it's illogical to think that we can communicate through time.
それを信じる方がどうかしてる。
It'd be stranger to actually believe that.
（左門）≪今更　常識もないだろう≫
You're bringing up logic now?
First of all, we are indeed working across time.
≪第一
現実に　時を越えているんだ≫
Mahiro, activate the talisman,
真広　魔具を発動させろ！
and we can save Ms. Hakaze.
それで葉風さんを救える！
お前の望みもかなう。
Your wish will come true, too.
これ以上の悲劇は
避けられるんだ！
We can avoid further casualties.
≪しまった！≫
Damn it!
≪あの少年は
完全に間違っている≫
That boy is utterly wrong.
≪だが　それは関係ないのだ≫
But that's irrelevant!
≪魔具を発動させられたら→
If he activates the talisman,
私は　姫様を　ここに…
ここに戻せる≫
I will almost certainly have to return the princess.
≪いや　戻さざるをえない！≫
No...
I will have no other choice!
It doesn't matter whether he speaks truth or nonsense.
≪理屈など　でたらめでもいい≫
≪彼に引き金を引かせさえすれば
あの少年の勝ち！≫
If he can make the other boy pull the trigger, he will win.
≪いや　姫様が勝つ≫
Or rather...
The princess will win.
≪でたらめでも
結果は同じなのだ≫
Nonsense or not, the result is the same.
≪なんと狡猾な…≫
How unbelievably crafty.
≪一族の総力をかけた
本物の時間の檻を→
Will his trick break an actual prison of time that took the entire clan to forge?
そんな奇策で破ろうというのか≫
All by using nonsense?
≪ならん！　ならんぞ！≫
That cannot happen...
It cannot!
How can I prove there is a time shift?
≪だが　時間のずれを
どうやって証明すれば…≫
≪よし　焦ってる≫
Good. He's panicking.
≪この間に　真広と葉風さんが
動いてくれれば…≫
Now, if only Mahiro and Ms. Hakaze would take action.
≪また三人で
力を合わせることができれば→
If the three of us
succeed in combining our strengths,
勝てる≫
we can win.
≪勝てるはず！≫
We should be able to win.
ふん！
ガキン！
ゴォーー（戦闘機のエンジン音）
ふふっ。
バシューー！
They're here!
（宇津井）来たな。　近接航空支援！
We have close air support!
バシューー！
Return! Return! Return! Return!
（男たち）戻れ　戻れ　戻れ…。
（部下）哲馬殿！
結界第１層　もう　もちません！
Tetsuma!
The barrier will not withstand another strike!
Beautiful! Beautiful!
Damn it.
（哲馬）くそっ！
ヤツら　出し惜しみはなしか。
They're throwing everything they've got at us.
Fruit! Fruit!
Return! Return!
もはや　こちらも手段を選ばん。→
Then we will also do whatever it takes.
Beautiful! Beautiful!
結界第１層および　第２層の維持を
一時的に放棄！→
Temporarily divert power from the first and second barriers!
Fruit! Fruit!
Return! Return!
その人員を　復活の儀式に回せ！→
Concentrate that power toward the revival of the Tree of Exodus!
Beautiful! Beautiful!
儀式を加速させる！
（男たち）果実　果実。
We're going to speed up the ritual!
Fruit! Fruit!
（左門）
惑わされるな！　お前の友人は→
Do not be fooled!
Your friend has not proven the lack of a time differential.
時間がずれていないことを
証明していない。→
魔具を発動していい条件など
何一つ証明しておらんぞ！
He has not provided a single concrete reason to activate the talisman.
I don't need to provide proof; you're the one making an implausible claim!
≪吉野の理屈は　はったりくさい≫
Yoshino's theory sounds like a bluff.
≪リスクも　まだ高い≫
Siding with him is still a great risk.
What?
≪だが　そいつに乗れるだけの
舞台は作ってやがる≫
Yet he's managed to create a situation that makes the risk acceptable.
You're the one who should show us proof.
If Samon can't come up with anything,
You're the one claiming there's a time shift!
≪左門が
このまま　手を打てないなら→
条件的には　吉野の方が…≫
Yoshino seems like the better choice under the circumstances.
It's a logical fallacy!
It's a valid theory!
≪吉野の論は　かなり際どい≫
Yoshino's theory is pretty dodgy,
≪だが　左門の態度も腑に落ちん≫
but Samon is behaving questionably, as well.
≪時間の檻に
秘密があるからか？≫
Is it because there's a secret to this prison of time?
≪なら→
In that case
この強手
通すだけの価値はあるか≫
it may be worth forcing Samon's hand!
≪やはり
時間のずれを証明せねば→
It appears I have no other choice but to prove the time shift exists.
押し切られかねん≫
≪孤島と　ここに　２年のずれが
あるのは事実だというのに→
Even though it's completely true that two years separate the island from now,
証明に苦しめられるとは…≫
I'm the one who has to prove it!
≪あの骨は　確かに
島から持ち帰った姫様の…≫
Those bones I brought back from
the island do belong to the princess.
Brought back in...
≪一緒に持ち帰った？　はっ！≫
（左門）樽だ。
ん？
The barrel.
Huh?
その樽だ！
ん？
That barrel!
樽？
（左門）そうだ！→
Barrel?
That's right.
姫様のそばに樽はあるな？
あるはずだ!!
Isn't there a barrel near the princess?
There must be!
ごほっ…
ごほごほっ　ごほごほっ！
（通信）葉風さん？
（葉風）ああ　樽はある。
Ms. Hakaze?
Yeah, there is one.
（左門・通信）
私は樽を　姫様の骨と共に→
I retrieved the princess's bones from the island, along with that barrel.
孤島から持ち帰った。　つまり→
Meaning...
The barrel beside the princess and the barrel here are one and the same.
姫様のところにある樽と
ここにある樽は同じもの。
（左門）ここと孤島で
２年もの時間がずれているから→
As there is a two-year time shift,
同じ樽が
２つの場所で確認できるのだ！
the barrel can be verified to exist in both times at once!
同じ樽という証拠はないでしょう？
There's no proof that it's the same barrel though.
（左門・通信）だが　証拠があれば→
But if there was, it would also prove that there is a time shift.
時間のずれも証明されよう。→
なんでもいい。　姫様に
お前が適当に決めた言葉を→
Anyway...
Have the princess carve a word of your choice into the barrel.
樽のどこかに刻んでいただけ。
If the two barrels are different, nothing will happen.
２つの樽が違う樽なら何もない。→
だが　同じ樽であれば→
But if they are the same,
お前が
自由に選んだはずの言葉が→
the word that you, yourself, chose
今そこにある樽に
刻まれることになる。
will appear on that barrel.
いいでしょう。
Very well.
葉風さん　これから言う言葉を
書いてください。
Ms. Hakaze, please carve the following word.
（葉風・通信）分かった。
Got it.
ガシャン！
（通信）では　こう書いてください。
Then, please write this.
よし。
All right.
（葉風・通信）
書いたぞ。　樽の下辺りだ。
It's written there,
near the bottom.
分かりました。
Understood.
≪必ずあるはず…　決まりだ≫
It will be there without fail.
It is settled!
Ariel!
僕の言葉どおり刻まれています。
The word I told her is carved there.
なぜか　びっくりマークも
刻んでありますが…。
With an exclamation point for some reason.
Ariel!
I just felt like adding it.
ついでだ。
どうやら　この２つの樽は→
So this proves the two barrels are, in fact, the same.
同じ樽で間違いないな。
結論が出たようだな。
We seem to have reached a conclusion.
１つの樽が　別々の場所に
同時に存在することはできない。→
It is impossible for the same barrel to exist simultaneously in two different places.
できるのは　孤島と　ここで→
It can only be possible if it exists here in the present and there in the past!
大きく
時間がずれている場合だけだ！→
少年　証明終了だ。→
Young man, there is your proof.
お前の奇策は破れた！
Your theory has failed!
バシューー！
ドカン！
大したものだ。
こちらも　相当　消耗した。
Impressive.
I have expended quite a bit of energy.
再び　軍の戦力を削るのは
骨が折れよう。
It will cost me too much to attempt another attack on your forces.
（山本）ま…　待て…。
W-Wait...
≪（潤一郎）待ちなよ　魔法使い君。
Wait a sec, Mr. Mage.
（夏村）じゅ…　潤一郎殿。
M-Mr. Juunichiro...
（潤一郎）やあ。
もう少し　つきあっていきなよ。→
Hey!
Stick around a little longer.
ほら　お菓子もあるんだよ。
Look!
I even have snacks.
Mr. Juunichiro, what is this about?
（夏村）潤一郎殿　何を…。
（潤一郎）風が…。
The wind...
（左門）
すべて　はっきりしただろう。
Everything has come to light.
分かったら　お前も　不用意に
魔具を発動させようとするな。→
If you can see that, then do not rashly activate the talisman.
I will eventually bring you your sister's killer.
じき　お前の妹を殺した犯人を
連れてくるゆえ…。
いつまで　うなだれてんだよ！
Hey, snap out of it!
（葉風・通信）そうだ　吉野。
He's right, Yoshino!
（葉風）うなだれるな！　いや
先にうなだれた私が愚かだった。
Don't fall into despair.
Actually, I was foolish for letting myself despair!
うん？
（葉風）吉野　結論は違っていたが→
Yoshino, your conclusion may have been incorrect,
貴様の考え方は正しい。
but your way of thinking is correct.
この世の理は　私の味方だ。→
This world's logic favors me.
（通信）私も感じた。
左門は　何かを隠している。
I sensed something off, too.
Samon is hiding something.
あっ！
（葉風・通信）時間を越える方法は→
I don't know how to cross time yet,
まだ具体的には分からん。
だが　諦めるな！→
but don't give up!
Even if you two cannot do it,
（通信）貴様一人では無理でも
私の魔法の知識を重ねれば→
with the help of my magic,
we're going to find a way.
必ず見つけられる。
方法は　きっとある。
There will definitely be one!
Yeah, there should definitely be a way.
ああ　確かに　方法はありそうだな。
実際　声は時間を越えてるんだ。
Seeing as your voice is crossing time,
魔法を　どうにか応用すりゃ
肉体も越えられそうじゃねぇか。
you can probably find a way to get your body across time with magic.
おい　何を言っている。
ん？
Hey, what are you talking about?
Do you intend to ignore our agreement?
私との取り引きを無視する気か!?
約束が違うぞ！
This wasn't the deal!
約束は守るさ。
I'll keep my promise.
愛花を殺したヤツが
連れてこられれば→
If you can give me Aika's killer,
葉風も吉野も　切り捨てる。
I'll cut ties with Hakaze and Yoshino.
この魔具も　肝心の時間を→
And I won't activate this talisman without knowing the magic to cross through time.
（通信）越える魔法が分かんねぇのに
発動させたりはしねぇ。
だがな…。
うっ！
But you know what?
It pisses me off to think you were gloating over how you were about to trick us.
お前に　うまくだまして
出し抜いてやったって→
いい気になられるのは　むかつく。
So,
だから　時間を越える方法を
ちょいと考えてみるか→
I kind of feel like trying to find some magic to cross time.
って気分になっただけだ。
くっ…。
吉野　頭　切り替えろ。
Yoshino, change your thinking.
っていうか　お前
最初から　こうなるの狙ってたろ？
Or rather,
isn't this what you were aiming for all along?
Making Samon panic by throwing some ridiculous theory at him,
（通信）むちゃな仮説を
わざと　左門にぶつけて動揺させ→
then using that opportunity to lift Hakaze's despair.
葉風を立ち直らせる
きっかけにする。
Even changing my mind.
ついでに　俺も　そんな気にさせる。
狙ってなかったとは言わせねぇぞ？
I won't let you pretend that wasn't your intention.
（左門）≪そっ　そんな…≫
I-It can't be...
≪私が　あの少年の思惑に
はまっていただけだというのか!?≫
Are you saying that I was playing right into that boy's hand?!
Yoshino, you're surprisingly underhanded.
吉野…　貴様　意外に性格悪いな。
It's still a little early to celebrate.
喜ぶのは　まだ早いですよ。
愛花ちゃんを殺した犯人が
ここに連れてこられる前に→
We have to find a way to cross time
before Aika's killer is brought here.
時間を越える方法を
見つけなければいけません。
そうだな？　真広。
Right, Mahiro?
ああ。　その方法が　俺にとって→
Yeah.
It's possible that way won't work out.
都合の悪いものって可能性もある。
今の段階じゃ　葉風にはつけねぇ。
So at this point, I still can't choose Hakaze's side.
ただ→
However,
犯人が連れてこられるまでは→
until Aika's killer is brought to me,
その方法を考えるくらいは
してやるよ。
I'll help think of a way to retrieve Hakaze.
Fear not, Yoshino.
案ずるな　吉野。
今や風は　こちらに吹いている。→
The wind now blows in our favor.
（通信）
お前が　私を奮い立たせた時点で→
You turned the tide when you shook me out of my despair!
風向きは変わったのだ。
（葉風）では　破るぞ　時間の檻を。→
Very well. Let us break through this prison of time.
方法は　必ずある！
There must be a way!
kimi to miteta nagareboshi oikakete
Chasing the shooting star that we saw together
I chased the shooting stars I saw together with you
Reaching this place all alone
hitori bocchi konna toko made kiteta
Hiding the feelings I wanted to express to you
kinou kimi ni ienakatta kimochi o
kotoba no naka kakusu no
within words
tooku hanarete itemo douka todokimasu you ni
No matter how far we are separated,
please let it reach you
kono michi no saki ni matsu unmei nante
The fate waiting for us down this road
is not yet known
ima wa mada
dare mo mada
shiranai kedo
by anyone
To the future drawn by numbed fingers
kajikan da yubisaki de egaita mirai he
With you we can make it
kimi to nara ikerutte
nee sonna ki ga shiteta nda
That's what I feel
kitto
with certainty
You're in a bad mood.
（愛花）機嫌が悪いですね。
You know the killer's identity.
犯人が分かったんだ。
早く連れてこさせろよ。
Hurry up and bring the killer here.
（山本）うそ…。
（夏村）戦術的撤退だ！
No way.
Tactical retreat!
（葉風）まさか…。
It can't be...
（潤一郎）
男じゃないだろう！　違うかい!?
How can you call yourself a man?
Am I wrong?
（葉風）
いるかもしれんのだ…　ただ一人→
There may be one person
who could have escaped the web of magic!
魔法の網にかからぬ者が！
（左門）バ…　バカな！
I-I-Impossible!
Episode 11
Girl of Time